#### Contact

6613336585 (Mobile) ejane\_daung@yahoo.com

www.linkedin.com/in/erwina-jane-melendez-b49ab7106 (LinkedIn)

### Top Skills

Nursing Care Nursing Process Nursing Documentation

### Languages

Visayan

**English** 

**Tagalog** 

# Erwina Jane Melendez

Crown Diamond at Valentus

Bakersfield, California

### Summary

A highly skilled Registered Nurse with a degree in Bachelor of Science in Nursing, has previous hospital, SNF, and community experience, and has a strong commitment in providing quality nursing care while ensuring smooth nursing operations and regulatory compliance.

#### Skills:

- > Oversees the clinical operations (i.e. monitoring resident conditions, psychopharmacological drugs, restraint use, foley catheters, pressure ulcers, etc.) of the Nursing Department.
- > Assists the Director of Nursing Services in the design, implementation and evaluation of nursing systems that ensure consistent delivery of care and maintains and promotes resident rights.
- > Conducts nursing rounds on all units several times a day, including the beginning and end of shift.
- > Provides reports/recommendations as needed/required for the Director of Nursing Services concerning the operations of Nursing Services.
- > Assists the Director of Nursing Services in the development, implementation and evaluation of facility policies, procedures and guidelines on an annual and on-going basis (i.e. nursing, pharmacy, lab, physicians, medical records, etc.)
- > In the absence of the Director of Nursing Services, conducts staff meetings.

- > Assists the Director of Nursing Services in ensuring that residents are free from abuse, mistreatment and neglect.
- > Assists the Director of Nursing Services in ensuring nursing staff awareness and compliance with Federal and State regulations relative to resident rights issues.
- > Assists in Nursing administrative calls.

# Experience

Valentus
Crown Diamond
June 2018 - Present (2 years 2 months)

#### Brookdale

Assistant Director of Clinical Services (RN ADON) May 2016 - Present (4 years 3 months) Bakersfield, California

Rockport Healthcare Services- Rehabilitation Center of Bakersfield Assistant Director of Nursing Services, RN August 2015 - December 2016 (1 year 5 months) Bakersfield, California Area

# LifeHOUSE Properties- Lifehouse Parkview

1 year 11 months

Assistant Director of Nursing
May 2014 - August 2015 (1 year 4 months)

- > Oversees the clinical operations (i.e. monitoring resident conditions, psychopharmacological drugs, restraint use, foley catheters, pressure ulcers, etc.) of the Nursing Department.
- > Assists the Director of Nursing Services in the design, implementation and evaluation of nursing systems that ensure consistent delivery of care and maintains and promotes resident rights.
- > Conducts nursing rounds on all units several times a day, including the beginning and end of shift.

- > Provides reports/recommendations as needed/required for the Director of Nursing Services concerning the operations of Nursing Services.
- > Assists the Director of Nursing Services in the development, implementation and evaluation of facility policies, procedures and guidelines on an annual and on-going basis (i.e. nursing, pharmacy, lab, physicians, medical records, etc.)
- > In the absence of the Director of Nursing Services, conducts staff meetings.
- > Assists the Director of Nursing Services in ensuring that residents are free from abuse, mistreatment and neglect.
- > Assists the Director of Nursing Services in ensuring nursing staff awareness and compliance with Federal and State regulations relative to resident rights issues.
- > Assists in Nursing administrative calls.

RN Supervisor October 2013 - May 2014 (8 months)

St. John's HomeHealth RN January 2012 - October 2013 (1 year 10 months)

Partners in Care Foundation- MSSP RN Case Manager June 2011 - October 2013 (2 years 5 months)

LifeHOUSE Properties- Lifehouse Parkview RN Supervisor October 2010 - June 2011 (9 months)

### Education

Cebu City Medical Center College of Nursing
Bachelor's Degree, Registered Nursing/Registered Nurse · (2003 - 2007)